Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
集中できてないな　まだ体が迷っているんだ
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
震えていたんじゃ　コントロールしたってブレるんだ
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
ツキ
太陽も勝負運もなんも完全にこっち向いていないが
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
「やるしかないんだ」
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
状況は悪いが　ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないなぁ
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
展望はないが　度胸でクリアするしかないや
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
必要なもんは勝つプライド
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
それとも敗北の苦汁か
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
そう　すべては2つに1つ
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
操りたい運命の糸
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
絶好のゴールデンタイム　この手で掴め
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
渾身のポーカーフェイス　キメて仕掛けるよ
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
イリュージョンの世界へ引きずり込んで
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム　スルリと抜けて
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
栄光のボーダーライン　飛び越えるために
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
ハウメニー？　どれくらいの代償がいる？
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
I'll show you how we do things at Briggs.
ブリッグズ流を見せてやる
"How you do things at Briggs"?
ブリッグズ流
That's right.
そうだ
Lend us a hand, alchemist!
手伝え　錬金術師
Brother!
兄さん
You, too!
お前もだ
Hang on! We're...
待ってくれ　オレたちは
You were threatened and forced to help.
脅されて無理やり手伝わされた
No one can blame you for that, right?
これなら文句はあるまい
Who's this?
こいつは
He's our bro.
オレらのマブダチ
Okay. You're helping, too.
よし　手伝え
Pick up the pace! And don't spill any of it!
急げ　こぼすなよ
Buccaneer! Carry those to Gate 8!
バッカニア　８番ゲートだ
Yes, sir!
はっ
Charge!
突撃
Shove him into the elevator!
ヤツをエレベーターに押し込め
What... a drag...
めんどくせぇ
Push! Push!
押せ　押すんだ
All right! We can do this!
よし　いけるぞ
Turret, turn to starboard!
砲身　右旋回
Yes, ma'am...
アイ　マム
Miles, send him away!
マイルズ　送れ
Aye, ma'am!
はっ
All right! We did it!
よし　いった
Where... am I?
ここ　どこ
今だ　やれ
Now! Let him have it!
Good job!
よっしゃ
Now what?
で　この後は
How do we throw him out of the gate?
どうやってこいつをゲートの外にほうり出すんだ
This stuff smells.
（臭っ…）
Move, brat!
どけ　赤チビ
Hey! One more round!
おい　もう一発
We're out of ammo!
弾切れですぜ
In that case...
だったら
That hurt...
痛っ
All right!
おしっ
It's north-blend fuel.
寒冷地仕様の混合燃料だ
It vaporizes even in extremely low temperatures,
and with that, it absorbs body temperature in no time.
極低温下でもおかまいなしに気化して
その気化熱であっという間に体温を奪う
加えてこのブリザード
On top of that, we're in the middle of a blizzard.
He'll freeze all the way to his brain.
脳みそまで即凍りつくぞ
So cold...
寒っ
My body...
体　動かない
...won't... move...
What... a drag...
めんどくせぇ
Hibernate until spring comes around, dimwit.
そこで春まで冬眠していろ　のろまめ
Buccaneer, haul these three down.
バッカニア　こいつらを連行しろ
Roger!
はっ
What?!
ちょちょちょ　なっなっなんで
W-W-Whoa!
W-W-Why?!
オレたち協力して
We helped you!
"You were forced to."
させられた
Wouldn't that be more convenient for you?
その方が都合がいいのだろう
And I'm not letting you get away until the identity of that monster becomes clear, so be prepared.
それに　あの怪物がなんなのか判明するまで
逃がさんから　そのつもりでいろ
うぅっ　寒っ
It's cold.
"Clang"?
ガチャ
Morning, Brother.
おはよう　兄さん
Oh, that's right.
ああ　そうだった
Yo! Did you have a nice nap?
よう　よく眠れたか
I did, but...
眠れたけどさ
So I hear you saved our men.
仲間を守ってくれたんだってな
Thanks.
サンキュー
That'll be 100 cenz.
１００センズ
This wasn't out of gratitude?!
お礼じゃねぇのかよ
Umm... are there any news?
あの　何か進展は
The advance unit went to check up on that hole.
先遣隊が例の穴を調べに行った
They should be back any moment now.
そろそろ戻ってくるころだ
Oh, and Major Miles is at the hospital.
ああ後　マイルズ少佐は病院だ
Hospital?
病院
He's there to see the guy who was injured while fighting Scar.
スカーとやり合ってケガした軍人のお見舞いだよ
Scar is up north, too?
スカーが北に
Oh, there you are.
おっ　いたいた
He's awake.
起きてるぞ
Thanks for yesterday.
昨日はありがとな
You saved our buddies' lives.
仲間が命拾いしたよ
You guys really care about your buddies, don't you?
あんたら　結束固いっつうか　仲間思いだな
We at Briggs consider ourselves a monolith.
オレたちブリッグズ兵は一枚岩よ
And since you saved our buddies, that makes you one, too.
仲間を助けてくれたお前も仲間だ
じゃあその仲間を早くここから
Then can't you let your buddy out of-
No can do.
そいつはできない相談だ
You guys really are a monolith...
確かに一枚岩だ
Apparently, Scar's body wasn't found at the scene of the accident.
事故現場からスカーの死体は発見されなかったそうだ
There's a possibility he's lurking in the area.
付近に潜伏している可能性があるな
Yes.
ええ
Good lord...
やれやれ
First, the cat... and now we also need to search for Scar?
このタイミングで白黒猫に加えてスカーの捜索とは
Understood.
了解した
Leave Scar to us and focus on getting better.
スカーの件は我々に任せて
養生したまえ
Wait a second.
待ちなさい
I want you all to stay out of this.
あなた方は引っ込んでいてください
The Ishbalan is my prey.
イシュヴァール人は私の獲物です
Unfortunately for you, we're not so soft as to let
a mass murderer do whatever he wants here at Briggs.
残念ながら
殺人鬼をのさばらせておくほど
ブリッグズの兵はぬるくない
We believe in the survival of the fittest.
ここの掟は弱肉強食
If you let your guard down for a second, you die. Understand?
油断すれば殺られる　分かるか
Talk shit again, and you'll never be able to leave the hospital.
なめた口利いていると二度と退院できなくなるぞ
We at Briggs have been commanded to take care of you.
貴様の面倒は　ブリッグズ支部が見ることになっている
So stay put.
おとなしくしていろ
Just as I remember. Ishbalans are so interesting.
イシュヴァール人はやはりおもしろい
Are you doing all right, Kimblee?
キンブリー　大丈夫かね
You got here sooner than I'd expected, Lieutenant General Raven.
これはお早いお着きで　レイブン中将
I rushed here after I heard about your injury.
知らせを聞いてすっ飛んできたよ
You had me worried.
心配で心配で
This is what you're worried about, right?
あなたが心配しているのは　これでしょう
Very well.
よろしい
Now, time to get to work.
では仕事だ
But as you can see, I'm...
しかし　私はご覧のとおり
I brought a doctor well-versed in alchemy.
錬金術を使える医者を連れてきた
And we have the stone.
そして石がある
You'll be well in no time.
あっという間に全快だよ
Eastern Alchemy is quite difficult.
錬丹術はなかなか難しいね
Especially this whole concept of the "veins of the dragon".
特にこの龍脈とやらがよく分からない
It's to describe the power running through the earth.
大地の気のことですよ
Power running through the earth?
大地の気
Simply put,
簡単に言うと　山の頂から噴出した後地下へと入り
it's a power that goes back into the ground after erupting from the summit of a mountain, and enriches the earth.
土地を潤していく力です
Think of it as a river that runs through the earth.
大地の中を流れる力の川とでもいいましょうか
By understanding that flow of strength, its entrances and exits...
その力の流れや　入り口出口を理解して使うと
You can apply it to practically anything.
これは万物に応用できる力なんですよ
When you say "anything", does this apply to the human body, as well?
万物ということは人体にも
Yes, it does!
はい
For example... your hip!
例えば　腰
My foot...
足が
Or, right here!
あるいは　ここ
Why did I feel that in my eyes after having my neck pressed?
首を押されて　なんで目に衝撃が
You need to take care of your body, Dr. Marcoh.
マルコーさん　体を大切にね
The power in your body is stagnant in many places.
あちこち力がよどんでますよ
I-I see now...
うっ　なっなるほど
So this is what makes long-distance transmutation possible.
これが遠隔錬成の理屈か
So your alchemy doesn't use the veins of the dragon?
錬金術は龍脈を使わないのですね
Yeah. We use the energy created by tectonic movements.
ああ　地殻運動のエネルギーを使っている
The immense amount of energy that is released by earthquakes and volcanic activity.
地震や火山活動で地中に放出される莫大なエネルギー
This country's alchemy uses that energy.
それを使うのがこの国の錬金術だ
But that's not it.
でも　違うんですよ
Ever since I stepped foot in this country, I felt like something was out of place...
この国に入ってから感じていた違和感
I finally realized what once I went underground in Central...
セントラルの地下ではっきりしたんですけど
...but this power, which flows beneath our feet...
足もとに流れているこの力は
...feels more like it's coming from thousands of people squirming about...
地殻運動のエネルギーというより
...rather than energy created by tectonic movement.
なんだか　たくさんの人が蠢いているような
でかいです
It's huge.
ちょっとした軍隊なら通れそうな穴です
A platoon should be able to get through.
それが緩やかなカーブを描いて　延々と続いています
The tunnel goes on indefinitely, following a loose curve.
ただ人の気配はまったくありません
But there aren't any signs of people down there.
馬を下ろせ
Take the horses down.
はっ
Yes, ma'am!
それからあいつらを連れてこい
And bring those three, too.
Wow... It really is huge.
すっげぇ
ほんとにでかいなぁ
これほどの仕込みに気づかず
I can't believe we let him break in without noticing all this was going on...
侵入を許すとは
So this is the first time Briggs has been invaded?
今まで入られたことはなかったんですか
私が着任してからはな
Since I came here, yes.
ただ２０年近く前に
But around twenty years ago, there was a case when our security guards were attacked during midwinter.
真冬に山岳警備兵が襲われる事件があった
謎の女に１か月
Apparently, a mysterious woman kept stealing food and supplies from them for an entire month.
食料や装備を奪われ続けたそうだ
真冬のブリッグズ山で１か月生き延びたぞ
I survived in Briggs in the winter for a month!
It has to be her...
あれだ
そろそろいいか
I guess this is far enough.
降りろ
Get off.
えっ
さて
Now...
ここなら人目を気にすることはない
You don't have to worry about anyone eavesdropping on us down here.
貴様らが知っていることを全部話せ
Tell me everything you know.
今度こそすべてだ
I mean everything.
隠し立てはするな
Don't hide anything.
あの怪物について尋ねたとき
When I asked you about the monster, you asked me to try to realize your situation, did you not?
貴様は言ったな　察してくれと
それすなわち　私が察してくれると信じての言葉
More or less, you believed that I would realize your situation.
切り捨てられてもおかしくないあの局面で
You could have been killed at any time in that situation, yet you still summoned those words.
貴様はあえてその言葉を絞り出した
自分の命に代えても　守らねばならんもの
So I figured you had something to protect,
even if it meant you'd lose your life doing so.
例えば　人質
For example, a hostage.
うそ　偽り　ごまかしはいらん
I want you to cut the bullshit.
真実を話せ
Tell me the truth.
力を貸してほしい
We need your help.
賢者の石　人造人間
Philosopher's stones... Homunculi...
キング·ブラッドレイ
King Bradley, and a man who is referred to as Father...
お父様と呼ばれる男
And the entire upper echelon is guilty....
軍上層部は真っ黒
そしてやはり人質か
So as we thought, people were being taken hostage.
幼なじみの機械鎧技師にマスタングの部下
A friend of yours who is an automail mechanic and Mustang's men...
東方司令部とはよく合同訓練をしていたから
We performed many joint drills with Eastern Headquarters, so I know Hawkeye and Havoc.
ホークアイやハボックは知っているぞ
失うには惜しいヤツらだ
It would be a big loss to lose them.
なんとかしたいな
I wish I could do something.
あの　マスタング大佐は
Umm... what about Colonel Mustang?
ああ　どうでもいい
Oh... I don't really care about him.
いっそ　とっとと失脚してくれれば
It would actually be better for me if he just falls, so I have one less rival to worry about.
ライバルが減って清々する
それより　これからどうするかだ
More importantly, we need to decide what to do now.
この地下道　貴様ら錬金術師はどう見る
How do you alchemists see this underground path?
このトンネルは
I don't think this tunnel was dug from Drachma.
おそらくドラクマから掘られたものじゃない
あくまで仮説だが
This is only a hypothesis, but it seems as though this tunnel was dug to create a large circle.
こいつはとてつもなく
大きな円を描くように掘られている
円
A circle?
錬金術において
A circle governs the circulation of power in alchemy and is an important factor.
円は力の循環を司つ重要なファクターだ
あとは方程式
Now, for the equation...
ファルマン少尉
Lieutenant Falman, do you know the major incidents within the country that resulted in a lot of bloodshed?
国内であった流血を伴う　大きな事件って分かるかな
流血
Bloodshed?
それが何か
How would that...
1558年７月　リヴィエア事変
The Riviere Incident in July of 1558.
Let's see... Riviere.
リヴィエアっと
1661年１０月　カメロン内乱
The civil war in Cameron in October of 1661.
1799年２月　ソープマン事件
The Soapman incident, February 1799.
That happened in Fisk.
場所はフィスク
1811年３月　ウェルズリ事件
The Wellsley Conflict, March 1811.
1835年１０月　第一次南部国境戦は
The First Southern Border Conflict occurred in
October of 1835, northwest of where South City is today.
現在のサウスシティ北西
1911年５月から
The Second Southern Border Conflict happened in May of 1911, just south of Fortsett.
フォトセットの南で第二次南部国境戦
西のペンドルトンは
What about Pendleton to the west?
隣国クレタとの戦いで　兵がかなり死んでる
Many soldiers have died there in the battles against Creta, a neighboring nation.
そして　1914年　リオールの暴動
And the riot in Liore, in 1914.
Severe casualties.
死者多数だ
Wai-
ちょっ
暴動って　どうして
A riot?! Why?!
リオールで偽教主の正体を暴いた後
Didn't we report the situation to Eastern Headquarters immediately after we exposed the fake priest?!
すぐ東方司令部に報告したよな
中央軍だよ
It was the Central army.
ヤツらが出張ってきて
They came and made the Eastern army withdraw.
東方軍をお払い箱にしたんだ
その後だ　リオールがメチャクチャになったのは
Liore turned into a mess after that.
そんな　くそっ
No way...
Dammit!
作業を続けろ　鋼の
Continue what you were doing earlier, Fullmetal.
分かってる
I know.
これで　各地をつなぐぞ
Now we're going to connect the dots.
なんてことだ
How could this be?!
第五研究所の地下にあったという錬成陣と
It's almost identical to the transmutation circle we found under Research Laboratory 5!
そっくりじゃないか
人の命を使うという賢者の石の陣か
A circle for creating a philosopher's stone, which uses human lives...
こんな巨大なもので石を作ったら
Just how many people will die with such a large transmutation circle?!
一体何人が犠牲になるんだ
この国を使って賢者の石を作ろうとしているのかと
I once asked Envy if they were trying to create a philosopher's stone using this country.
エンヴィーに聞いたことがある
だがヤツは笑って言った
But he laughed and told me I was close.
惜しい　いい線いってるとね
以前私はエドワード君に
In the past, I told Edward that he'd surely be able to realize the real truth, which lies beyond the truth.
君なら真実の奥の更なる真実に気づくだろうと言った
真実とは賢者の石の材料が生きた人間であること
What I meant by the "truth" was that the stones are made of live humans.
真実の奥とは　それを指導した者たちの存在
And what I meant by "beyond the truth" is the existence of the ones behind it.
更なる真実とは国土全部を使っての賢者の石の錬成
And the truth beyond the truth is the transmutation of a philosopher's stone using the entire nation.
But that's not where it ends.
だが　そこで終わりではない
最終的にヤツらは何をしようとしているのか
We don't know what they're planning to do in the end.
君が探している不老不死の法も
We also don't know about immortality, which is what you're looking for.
だから　賢者の石に求めてはいけない
So you mustn't long for a philosopher's stone.
私の知識と君の錬丹術の知識とで
We must decipher this research by combining my knowledge of alchemy and your knowledge of Eastern Alchemy.
なんとしてもこの研究書を読み解こう
はい
Right.
いちばん古いのは　1558年
The oldest one was in 1558...
アメストリス建国後すぐだな
Right after Amestris was founded.
宣戦布告なしに
Without even a declaration of war, Amestris invaded Riviere, which was once a neighboring country...
当時隣国だったリヴィエアに戦争をふっかけ
あっ　ちょっと待て
Hang on!
これは
This is...
すべての事件に軍が関係している
The military is involved in every one of these incidents.
えっ
クーデター　内乱　リオールもそうだ
The coup d'etat... the civil wars... and Liore, too.
中央軍が出てきて　事を大きくしている
The Central Army came out and poured oil on the flames.
建国のときから
Ever since this nation was created?!
我が国は初め領土の小さな国だったが
Our country started out as a small nation, but we expanded by annexing the small countries around us.
周囲の小国を併合しながら広がってきた
この円を作り出すため
So it was to create this circle?
ヤツらは
So it wasn't their plan to use this country to do something, but they created this country to realize their task.
この国を利用して何かをしようとしているのではなく
何かをするためにこの国をつくり上げたのか
我が国を
Our country...
じゃあヒューズさんは
So, Mr. Hughes...
ああ　殺される前に賢者の石の錬成陣を見ている
Yeah. He saw the transmutation circle for the stone before he died.
それに軍法会議所勤務だったから
Since he worked in the building they have strategy meetings in,
he had access to more resources than anyone else.
軍の事件を調べるのに事欠かない
この国がおかしいってことにいち早く気づいて
He was the first to realize there was something wrong with this country-
軍の狗　国家錬金術師よ
Dog of the military. State Alchemist!
お前はこの国が何をしようとしているのか
Do you have any idea what this country is trying to do?!
知っているのか
Do you really think all this prosperity was created with the powers of humans only?
今の繁栄が自分たちの力だけで成し遂げられたと
思っているのか
知れば
If you did  know, you'd understand why I'm doing this!
私のやろうとしていることが分かるはずだ
気に入らんぞ
I don't like this!
これを見るかぎり　次に血を見るのは
Looking at the pattern, the next area that will see bloodshed...
残っているのは　このブリッグズ周辺だけではないか
The only area left is Briggs!
セントラルのヤツら
What do those pigs at Central plan to do with my castle?!
私の城で何をしようとしている
閣下
Major General!
すぐにお戻りください
Please return to base at once.
セントラルのレイブン中将がお見えになっています
Lieutenant General Raven has come to visit from Central.
考える間も与えてくれんか
So they're not even giving us time to think, huh?
アームストロング少将
Major General Armstrong.
あなたに頼みたいことがある
There's something I'd like to ask of you.
レイブン中将にカマ掛けてみてくれないか
Could you try and trick Lieutenant General Raven?
レイブン中将閣下
I'm sorry for making you wait, Lieutenant General Raven.
お待たせして申し訳ありません
いや　気にするな
No, worry not.
急に押しかけた私が悪い
It's my fault for coming here without advance notice.
アームストロング少将はすぐに戻ります
Major General Armstrong will be back shortly.
どうぞこちら
Please, follow me-
ああ　そうだ
Oh, that's right.
客人を連れてきた
I've brought a guest with me.
マイルズ少佐
Major Miles, do you mind giving him a tour of the fort?
彼に砦の中を見せてやってくれないか
よろしく　マイルズ少佐
Nice to meet you, Major Miles.
ウィンリィのアップルパイ
Winry's apple pie.
元の体に戻ったら食べたいって
The thing I said I'd like to eat when I get my body back.
でも　もうそんなこと考えてるだけじゃ
I guess we have more important things to think about now.
ダメなのかもしれないね
心配しなくてもたらふく食えるさ
Don't worry, you'll be able to eat it someday.
体を取り戻して
After we get our bodies back and beat the crap out of those guys planning to use this country for their own goals.
この国で好き放題やらかそうとしてるヤツらに
吠え面かかせてやったらな
うん
Yeah.
バタバタして申し訳ありません　閣下
Sorry for the mess, Lieutenant General.
敵の襲撃を受けまして
We were attacked by the enemy.
襲撃
Attacked?
なんとか撃退しましたが
We were able to drive it off,
but the thing was... what you'd call a monster.
これがまあ　いわゆる化け物というやつで
化け物　というと
What do you mean by monster?
殺しても死なないのです
It didn't die no matter what we did to it.
Oh, my.
ほほう　それはまた
That sounds troublesome.
私はドラクマの生物兵器だとにらんでいるんですが
Personally, I think it's a biological weapon from Drachma, but the Elric Brothers...
エルリック兄弟が
たまたま鋼の錬金術師と　その弟を保護したのです
We've taken in the Fullmetal Alchemist and his younger brother by chance.
化け物について何か知ってるふうなのですが
It seems as though they know something about the monster but won't say anything.
何もしゃべらない
大総統府直轄の国家錬金術師が
It could be a disaster if a state alchemist who works with the Führer President is a Drachman spy, so we've arrested them.
ドラクマのスパイであっては大問題ですから
牢につないでおきました
取り調べなさいますか
Would you like to see them?
ん　そうだな
I guess so.
何もしゃべらないのだな
They really won't say anything?
ええ
Yes.
ここに来た目的も　生体錬成の研究がどうのと
They also claim they came here to research organic transmutation or something.
They're being quite ambiguous. I couldn't doubt them more.
なんとも歯切れが悪く　怪しいことこのうえない
拷問してでも吐かせようかと思いましたが
I thought about torturing it out of them, but I'm technically a woman, too.
私も女の端くれ
あんな子供をいたぶるなんて
I couldn't lay a finger on a child like that.
My heart would be crushed...
心が痛んでとてもとても
言うねぇ
Yeah, right.
心臓まで氷でできている女王様が
That queen's made of ice to the core.
難攻不落なブリッグズの北壁と称される君も
So even you, who holds the title of "The Northern Wall of Briggs", has a soft spot for children, huh?
子供には弱いか
私も本来なら
It wouldn't be odd to have a child or two at my age,
but I'm totally behind in those affairs.
子供の１人や２人はいてもおかしくない年なのですが
すっかり行き遅れてしまいまして
何を言う
What are you talking about?
君なら引く手あまただろうに
You must be much sought after by the men.
いえいえ
No, no.
まったく年は取りたくないものですね
It's such a sad experience to age, isn't it?
私は老いが恐ろしい
I'm absolutely horrified of aging.
あのドラクマの生物兵器
That biological weapon from Drachma had a wonderful body.
あれはすばらしい体を持っていました
不死身の体　夢のようではありませんか
An immortal body.
Isn't it like a dream?
夢でない日が近づいている　と言ったらどうするね
What if I were to tell you that it may not be long before it isn't just a dream?
なあ　少将
Say, Major General...
完全な不死の軍団に興味はないか
Are you interested in a perfect, immortal army?
くらいついた
He fell for it!
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
何処までも行けるキミとなら
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
一人じゃ歩けない道も二人なら
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
鼻歌歌いながら歩けるんだ
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
キミがいれば幸せ
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
力に従え　それが弱肉強食
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
"Obey the ones with power".
That's the true meaning of the law of the jungle.
その言葉に縛られたくないならば
If you don't wish to be bound by that, obtain greater power.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
更に大きな力を持つがいい
力には力で対抗すべき瞬間があるのだから
Because there's always times one must fight power with power.
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第三十六話　家族の肖像
Episode 36, Family Portrait.
男は決意を胸に旅立つ
Men set out on journeys with determination in their hearts.